https://www.greenbelt.org.uk/privacy/#where-we-collect-your-information

TicketsSupportNews
CLOSE TicketsAboutWhat is Greenbelt?Our ManifestoWho we areMade In PalestineAboutEventsSupport the artistsMarketplaceInfoEssential InfoAccessAccommodationTravelA greener festivalSupportMediaTalksPodcastVideosPhotosBlogLook Back2020 Wild At Home2019 Wit and Wisdom2018 Acts of the ImaginationCommunionNewsletterShow AllWe may collect your personal information from a variety of sources. This privacy notice outlines in more detail what we collect, where we collect it,  how we use it and how we keep it safe.We use a system called SheepCRM to manage all of our sources of data and consent. Visit the Update My Preferences section to tell us how you would like to hear from us.Update your PreferencesVisit our SheepCRM Privacy Page  to tell us your communication preferences. After submission you will also be given the opportunity, if you wish, to create an account in the Sheep App and view all the consent details we currently hold on you.Who we areOur VisionGreenbelt believes that things often kept apart can and should be held together. Things like artistry and activism, spirituality and politics, faith and justice. It is a festival where these things belong together and where all are welcome.As a charity we rely on our supporters, volunteers, partners, staff and many other people who work with us to build the festival once a year, and increasingly at other events year round. To be able to do this we need to use personal data and we take the privacy of such data very seriously. This privacy notice explains our approach.Our detailsGreenbelt is Greenbelt Festivals, a company limited by guarantee.Company number: 1812893Charity number: 289 372ICO registration number: Z5930969In relation to the personal data you provide to us and which is used by us, Greenbelt is the data controller, i.e. we decide how your data is used. The ways in which we use your data are outlined in this Privacy Notice.Contacting usIf you would like to make an enquiry about data protection, update the information we hold about you, request or opt out of receiving marketing communications from us or change the way we process your information (see ‘Your rights’ section at the end of this document), you can let us know in the following ways:Email: myprivacy@greenbelt.org.uk
Online: via our SheepCRM Privacy Page Post: Data Administrator, Greenbelt Festivals, The Nest, Church House, 86 Tavistock Place, London, WC1H 9RT
Phone: 0207 329 0038If you wish to make a complaint about how your personal information has been used, please contact us in the following ways:
Email: myprivacy@greenbelt.org.uk
Post: Data Administrator, Greenbelt Festivals, The Nest, Church House, 86 Tavistock Place, London, WC1H 9RT
Phone: 0207 329 0038Alternatively, you are entitled to raise a concern to the Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO) without first referring your complaint to us. See here for more information.DEFINITIONSa)  Personal data is information about a living individual which is capable of identifying that individual. Identification can be by the information alone or in conjunction with any other information in the data controller’s possession or likely to come into such possession.b)  Processing is anything done with/to personal data, including storing it.c)  The data subject is the person about whom personal data are processed.d)  The data controller is the person or organisation who determines the how and what of data processing.e)  The GDPR is the General Data Protection Regulation 2016/679 which governs the processing of personal data.WHAT INFORMATION WE COLLECT ABOUT YOUWe will process some or all of the following where necessary to perform our tasks:Names, titles, and aliases, photographs;Contact details such as telephone numbers, addresses, email addresses and IP addresses;Where you provide them to us, we will process personal information such as gender, age, date of birth, marital status, nationality, education/work histories, academic/professional qualifications, hobbies, family composition, and dependants;Where you provide them to us, we will process sensitive classes of information that may include physical or mental health details, racial or ethnic origin, religious or other beliefs, trade union membership and information about offences/alleged offences;Where you pay to attend an event, buy merchandise or make donations, we will process financial identifiers such as bank account numbers, payment card numbers, security code, expiry date and payment/transaction identifiers (and for Gift Aid purposes, UK taxpayer status).WHERE WE COLLECT YOUR INFORMATIONGreenbelt collects your personal data when you interact directly with us. This could be when you buy tickets to a festival or other event; offer to volunteer at a festival or other event (or apply for a job with us); sign up to become an Angel (donor) or make a donation; buy merchandise online or at a festival or other event; sign up to a mailing list; or provide your data to us over the phone, by email, via the website and app, via physical mail, or in person e.g. at a festival or other event.If you have specific requirements in relation to a festival or other event e.g. in relation to accessibility or involving children, we may collect details of such requirements (which may involve you providing information about mental or physical health).When you engage with Greenbelt’s social media accounts, we might also obtain your personal data through your use of platforms such as Facebook, Twitter or Instagram depending on your settings or the privacy notices of these social media and messaging services. To change your settings, please refer to their privacy notices which will tell you how to do this.When you visit our websites, we gather general information about how you use them, as well as information about the type of device you are using to access them (e.g. phone, tablet, PC). This data helps us to create a better online experience for you; for example, make it easier for you to find what you’re looking for or fix elements that make the website difficult to use.CookiesWe use cookies – (small text files that a web browser stores on your device which track, save and store information, and may or may not expire when you close your browser). In general, cookies are used to retain user preferences, store information for things like shopping carts, and provide anonymised tracking data to third party applications like Google Analytics. As a rule, cookies will make your browsing experience better. However, you may prefer to disable cookies on our websites and on others. The most effective way to do this is to disable cookies in your browser. We suggest consulting the Help section of your browser or taking a look at the About Cookies website which offers guidance for all modern browsers.HOW WE USE YOUR INFORMATIONWe use your personal data for the following purposes:To plan, organise, administer and manage our annual festival and year round events;To build up a picture of our customer/supporter profile;To keep you up to date with news of our annual festival, year round events, activities and other information;To process a payment that you have made for tickets or merchandise;To process a donation that you have made (including Gift Aid information);To administer and manage our employees and volunteers (including recruitment);To maintain our own accounts and records;To process a grant;To process an application for a role.Legal basis for processing your personal information? Greenbelt relies on the following legal bases for processing personal data:Consent of the data subject: The data subject has given consent to the processing of his or her data for one or more specific purposes e.g. to receive newsletters such as Dispatches; reply to emails and correspondence.Performance of contract: Processing is necessary for the performance of a contract to which the data subject is party – Greenbelt will rely on this basis:To process payments for tickets and/or merchandise;to contact customers about a festival or other event they are attending;to collect feedback from customers following the event.Processing is necessary for the legitimate interests of the data controller or a third party, except where such interests are overridden by the interests, rights or freedoms of the data subject – Greenbelt will rely on this basis to:Send thank you emails or letters in response to donations made to us;Send thank you emails or letters upon termination of regular giving arrangements;Record donation details on our database;Make Gift Aid claims;Communicate with volunteers in respect of the festival or event for which they are Volunteering and during the following year to see if they would like to volunteer again.Continue to communicate with data subjects already on our database, from whom we have not yet received consent for up to one year after the GDPR comes into force to give those data subjects the opportunity to complete a consent form if they would like to do so;To keep a record of correspondence and any associated documents, if you contact us with a question, comment, compliment or complaint, so that we have the information available in the event of a follow-up, dispute or investigation.If you would prefer we do not use your personal information in this way, or want to change the way you hear from us, please contact us in one of the following ways:Email: myprivacy@greenbelt.org.uk
Online: via our SheepCRM Privacy Page Post: Data Administrator, Greenbelt Festivals, The Nest, Church House, 86 Tavistock Place, London, WC1H 9RT
Phone: 0207 329 0038WHO WE SHARE YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION WITH AND WHYYour personal data will be treated as strictly confidential. It will only be shared with third parties where it is necessary for the performance of our tasks; where we are legally required to share your personal data; where we share your personal data to protect Greenbelt or another individual; or where you first give us your prior consent. We will not, under any circumstances, share with or sell your personal data to any third party for marketing purposes and you will not receive offers from other organisations as a result of giving your details to us.It is likely that we will need to share your personal data with some or all of the following (but only where necessary):Our agents, servants and contractorsThese may include commercial service providers tomanage our online Box Office e.g. Ticketsolve;process online card payments* e.g. Realex;process donations* e.g. Charities Aid Foundation;maintain our database software e.g. SheepCRM;send out emails e.g. MailChimp;manage administration of performers e.g. Marcato.You can find the Privacy Notices for such service providers on their websites.*Please note that Greenbelt does not store payment card details on its systems.Gift AidIf you choose to include Gift Aid with a donation to us, then we will also ask for your address and UK taxpayer status as this information is required by law. You can read more about how Gift Aid works here. This information is needed for us to fulfil our obligations under tax (sections 413 to 430 Income Tax Act 2007) and charity law. Information associated with Gift Aid declarations must be retained for 7 years. This information will be shared with HMRC for tax regulation purposes and may also be shared with the Fundraising Regulator and the Charity Commission in the event of an enquiry or investigation.DATA PROTECTION AND INTEGRITYAt Greenbelt, we take data protection and integrity very seriously.we protect your personal information in a range of ways including secure servers, firewalls and SSL encryption;we follow payment card industry (PCI) security compliance requirements when processing credit card payments;we operate a policy of restricted, password controlled, access to any of your information which is stored on our systems; only authorised staff and key volunteers have access to your personal information, and only if essential. They are trained and understand the policies, processes and protocol for keeping it safe. Transfer of personal information outside the European Economic Area (EEA)Where information is transferred outside the EEA, we ensure that appropriate safeguards are in place to protect your information to the same or an equivalent level as would be found in UK and EU data protection legislation. One of the organisations we work with, our email service provider Mailchimp, processes personal information in the USA and has verified its data processing standards meet the EU-US Privacy Shield, which sets out clear safeguards and transparency responsibilities for US-based organisations processing personal information from EU citizens.HOW LONG WE KEEP YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATIONIn general, we will endeavour to keep personal data only for as long as we need it. This means that we may delete it when it is no longer needed.We will retain the personal data of a data subject on our database whilst the data subject remains an active supporter of Greenbelt as demonstrated by any of the following:buying tickets for/attending a festival or other eventbuying merchandiseopening electronic communications;making a donation;responding to social media posts;volunteering for Greenbelt;in any other way demonstrating their active support for Greenbelt.We will delete from our database the personal data of a data subject where the data subject is no longer an active supporter of Greenbelt (as demonstrated above) in which case the personal data will be deleted after 5 years have elapsed from the last occasion on which the data subject demonstrated active support for Greenbelt.We will retain Gift Aid declarations and associated paperwork for 7 years after the the most recent donation was made by the data subject.YOUR RIGHTSUnless subject to an exemption under the GDPR, you have the following rights with respect to your personal data:The right to request a copy of your personal data which Greenbelt holds about you;The right to request that Greenbelt corrects any personal data if it is found to be inaccurate or out of date;The right to request your personal data is erased where it is no longer necessary for Greenbelt to retain such data;The right to withdraw your consent to the processing at any time;The right to request that Greenbelt provides you with your personal data and, where possible, transmits that data directly to another data controller, (known as the right to data portability), (where applicable);The right, where there is a dispute in relation to the accuracy or processing of your personal data, to request a restriction is placed on further processing;The right to object to the processing of personal data, (where applicable);The right to lodge a complaint with the Information Commissioners Office.Please note that if you ask us not to contact you, we will keep some basic information about you on our suppression list in order to avoid sending you unwanted materials in future.How to ask us to access, amend or delete your informationIf you would like to:Tell us that your contact details have changed;Advise us that we have incorrect, out-of-date or inaccurate details for you;Ask us to stop sending you information or communications;Have your details removed from our database;please contact us in one of the following ways:Email: myprivacy@greenbelt.org.uk
Online: via our SheepCRM Privacy Page Post: Data Administrator, Greenbelt Festivals, The Nest, Church House, 86 Tavistock Place, London, WC1H 9RT
Phone: 0207 329 0038CHILDREN’S INFORMATIONWhile we do not actively collect information from children (under 18s), we appreciate that our customers and supporters are of all ages. Where appropriate, we will always ask for consent from a parent or guardian to collect information about children. We have clear rules on safeguarding of children and the collection of children’s information will be managed with appropriate safeguards in place.APPLYING FOR A ROLE WITH GREENBELT?Your CV, covering letter and application form for any role with Greenbelt will be used during the recruitment process to short-list suitable candidates for interview and to select the candidate to whom the role will be offered. During the recruitment process we may perform some checks on your identity, your right to work in the UK, your eligibility to work with vulnerable people and any past employment and personal references. If your application is successful, this information will then form part of your personnel file. We delete the personal information of unsuccessful applications 1 year after the application process ends in case there are follow-up queries about the process, unless a  candidate requests that we keep their details for  longer. Statistical information like ethnicity, sexuality and disability is kept to ensure that our recruitment processes are inclusive and not discriminatory, but this is completely anonymised.CHANGES TO THIS NOTICEWe keep this Privacy Notice under regular review and we will place any updates on our website. If we make a significant change, we will notify you.If we wish to use your personal data for a new purpose, not covered by this Privacy Notice, then we will provide you with a new notice explaining this new use prior to commencing the processing and setting out the relevant purposes and processing conditions. Where and whenever necessary, we will seek your prior consent to the new processing.This Notice was last updated on the 6th August 2018.
This site uses cookies: Find out more.OK, thank you
